Sarah Duman

2690 Nathaniel Rochester Hall, Rochester NY 14623 716.574.8728

snd3070@rit.edu

March	23.	201	1
1114161	40,	201	

Dear RIT Center for Residence Life,

I am writing to express my interest in Community Advocate Graduate Assistantship within the Center for Residence Life. I was made aware of this position and encouraged to apply by Kristy Cragg and Wendy Stapf, who are my current supervisors for the RIT BCGABC Residence Life Area Senior Resident Adviser position I am currently employed in. I am very happy to have this opportunity to apply for this position this year.

I feel that I am a qualified candidate for this position based on the experiences I have had in various leadership positions over the course of my student career at RIT. Through the RA position, the SRA position, leadership roles in the RIT Society of Women Engineers (Treasurer and President), and work study position in the RIT Honors program, I have learned a lot about myself as an individual and a leader. I have gained leadership, communication, time management and teamwork skills through each of these positions. I hope to continue to utilize these skills next year to have a positive influence RIT community members living in the Apartment areas across campus, as well as to challenge myself with new experiences and responsibilities.

I am very excited to be further considered for this position. My involvement with the RIT Center for Residence Life over the past three years has been one of the most rewarding experiences I have had in my collegiate career at RIT. I look forward to this application process and learning more about the Community Advocate Graduate Assistantship role.

Thank you very much for your time and consideration.

Sincerely,

Sarah Duman

SARAH N. DUMAN

snd3070@rit.edu

155 Nokomis Parkway Cheektowaga, NY 14225 2690 Nathaniel Rochester Hall Rochester, NY 14623 (716) 574-8728 (cell)

OBJECTIVE

Obtain a Graduate Assistantship in the RIT Center for Residence Life for the 2013-2014 Academic Year.

EDUCATION

Rochester Institute of Technology (RIT), Rochester, NY

B.S. in Industrial Engineering, M.E. in Engineering Management. Expected May 2014

Minor in Economics

RIT Honors Program Member

GPA: 3.7/4.0

RELEVANT COURSES

Engineering Management, Design Project Management, Experiential Leadership,

Honors Engineering- Leadership, Ethics and Sustainability

SKILLS

Leadership, Project Management, Conflict Resolution, Time Management

EXPERIENCE

RIT Center for Residence Life

Senior Resident AdviserAugust 2011 - PresentResident AdvisorAugust 2010 - August 2011

The Resident Advisor is a para-professional staff member of the Center for Residence Life who is responsible for developing a comprehensive residential experience for on-campus students and specifically for a community within an assigned area. The RA job can be broken down into six major components each representing a necessary and valued piece of the residential experience for our students. The responsibilities include, but are not limited to: Educator, Community Builder, Helper, Team Member, Leadership, and Administrator.

Like the Resident Adviser, the Senior Resident Adviser is a para-professional staff member of the Center for Residence Life who is responsible for developing a comprehensive residential experience for on-campus students and specifically for a community within an assigned area. The Senior Resident Adviser also performs the role of mentor and leader for other Resident Advisers on staff, including quarterly advising sessions. The Senior Resident Adviser also helps the Residence Coordinator with developing weekly meetings, staff development activities, and any other tasks that the Residence Coordinator chooses to delegate to them.

Toyota Motor Engineering & Manufacturing North America, Inc.

Project Planning and Management Co-op

March 2012 – August 2012

Assisted the Tundra Project Management Team. Responsibilities included ECI processing, master schedule development, drawing/sourcing coordination, color parts coordination, milestone management, and CV special condition parts tracking for current development project. Also led a working group for a delayed SOP project, which involved schedule re-coordination with Toyota/suppliers, and organized as well as presented in the project kickoff held at the manufacturing site in Texas (TMMTX).

WE@RIT

Summer 2011 Co-op

May 2011- August 2011

Supported the WE@RIT office as a member of a multidisciplinary team that focused on the curriculum development for WE@RIT's Summer Engineering camp for girls and their pre-orientation program for incoming female freshmen as well as leading these events. The co-op required knowledge of the engineering design process, research into new technologies and engineering studies, as well as personal skills such as communication, organization and leadership.

ACTIVITIES

RIT Society of Women Engineers (SWE):

President
Treasurer
Fundraising Chair
RIT Honors Complementary Learning Advisor

May 2012- Present May 2011- March 2012 May 2010-May 2011 October 2010- May 2012